bournemouth.ac.uk 2019-12-28

# Website privacy & cookies policy | Bournemouth University

We recognise the importance of your personal privacy. This privacy notice sets out how we use and protect any information that you give us when you use our website. By using our website, you are protected under the relevant data protection and electronic privacy laws.

The Data Protection Legislation (“the DP legislation”) regulates the use of personal data and sets requirements for protecting it. It seeks to balance an individual’s right to privacy with the need of organisations to use information about individuals for legitimate purposes.

The DP Legislation refers to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) which came into force on 25 May 2018 and additional UK data protection legislation which makes further provision about when and why personal data can be processed and the rights of individuals in relation to their personal data.

The Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations (PECR) sits alongside the DP Legislation and the GDPR. It gives people specific privacy rights in relation to electronic communications. This includes scenarios such as browsing websites which utilise cookies (and similar technologies). Such technologies allow websites to recognise you and store some information about your preferences or past actions. The objective being to make your experience the website more pleasant and usable.

Our approach to data protection compliance is set out in our [Data Protection Policy for Staff and BU Representatives (docx 127kb)](http://intranetsp.bournemouth.ac.uk/policy/Data%20Protection%20Policy%20for%20Staff%20and%20BU%20Representatives.docx). That Policy contains references to other key BU policies and processes relevant to data protection, including information security policies.

BU’s Data Protection Officer has overall responsibility for managing data protection within BU and communicating with individuals about our data protection compliance. The Data Protection Officer can be contacted on [dpo@bournemouth.ac.uk](mailto:dpo@bournemouth.ac.uk) or 01202 962472.

## What information do we collect from our website?

Sometimes we need to ask you for information so that you can do things on or through our website – like registering for an event or applying for a course. The information we are likely to collect for these purposes includes your name, address, telephone number and email address, and can even include things like dietary requirements or qualifications.

If we do collect personal data through our website, we will make it clear when are collecting personal information and we will explain what we intend to do with it. We will also refer to the relevant Privacy notices for further information.

We also use Hotjar, third-party software which provides us with:

  * Heat maps – these are visual representations of how website visitors have interacted with web pages, for example how far down the page they get and what links they interact with. This is aggregated data from thousands of page views, and cannot be used to identify individuals;
  * Session Recordings – Hotjar records information such as mouse movements and clicks and displays these as session recordings that our web team can watch back. These recordings are anonymous and cannot be linked to any individuals. They’re used to help us better understand what issues our website visitors are facing and what we can do to improve the site experience for them.

## Does the website use cookies?

When you visit our website, we collect information about you via cookies - small pieces of code that enables us to make sure the web page is displaying correctly. The information we gather through cookies includes things such as your geographical location and your computer's IP address. We don't gather any other data that might considered personal data using cookies.

These cookies help us to provide you with a better website, by monitoring which pages you find useful and which pages you don't. In order to-do this we currently rely on your ‘implied’ consent under PECR to-do this. In light of GDPR and a new e-privacy regulation (replacing PECR) we are reviewing our position. Meanwhile, if you want more control over your cookies, you can do this through your internet browser. More information can be found below under ‘disabling cookies’.

## Two types of cookies are used on this website:

  * Session Cookies. These are temporary cookies, which only exist for the period you access the website (or more strictly, until you close the browser after accessing the website). Session cookies help the website remember what you chose on the previous page, therefore avoiding having to re-enter information.
  * Persistent Cookies. These are cookies which remain on your device after you have visited our website. These cookies help us identify you as a unique visitor (by storing a randomly generated number).

The length of time a cookie will remain on your device will depend on the type of cookie.

We use Google Analytics cookies to see which pages are being looked at. This helps us analyse web data and improve our website - we only use this information for statistical analysis.

When you use our Course Search facility, we use a cookie that remembers which course you were looking at when you select 'Apply Online'. This then pre-selects that course on the application form to speed things up for you. This cookie expires after three hours. The BU online application system also automatically issues your computer with a cookie which enables the web page to display properly in your browser.

We also use third-party cookies in our email campaigns, mainly sent using an email marketing tool called dotMailer. These are used to monitor how many people open the emails we send and track which links they select within the email. You can find dotMailer's privacy policy on the [dotMailer website](http://www.dotmailer.com/terms/privacy-policy/).

Our website uses Google Analytics Display Advertising Features, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and YouTube to provide remarketing and other advertising services and features. This website, and third party vendors (including Google) use the Google Analytics cookie and other first-party and third party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to advertise online by seeing which pages are being looked at and to inform, optimise and show ads to you based on your past visits to our website. These ads may be shown to third party vendors, including Google, on sites across the internet.

The cookies are also used together to report on ad viewings, ad services and related visitor interactions within our website. In addition our website also uses data aggregated from Google’s Internet-based advertising or third party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) for general website reporting and improvement.

## Disabling cookies

This website does _not_ use cookies to collect personally-identifiable information about you. During your visits to our website you may notice some cookies which are unrelated to us. We do not control dissemination of these cookies and you should check the relevant third party websites for more information. You can disable cookies set by this or any other website by adjusting the settings on your internet browser. However, if you do so, some parts of our website might not work properly for you. To find out more, visit [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/). 

Find out how to manage cookies on popular browsers:

Visitors to our website can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customise Gdisplay Network ads by using [Ad settings provided by Google](http://www.google.co.uk/settings/ads/anonymous), or by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

Google also provides website visitors [Google Analytics opt-outs](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) for the web, which provides a browser add-on for opting out of Google Analytics tracking altogether.

## What do we do with the information we gather?

Any personal information we gather will only be used in accordance with the DP legislation, GDPR and PECR. We never sell or lease your personal information to third parties without your permission. We may use data to analyse demographic and other statistical information about the popularity and effectiveness of our website, but we'll only disclose that information in aggregate form, so individual users cannot be identified.

## How can I control my personal information?

You can control how and when we collect your personal information via our website in the following ways:

  * When you are asked to fill in a form on the website you will control over what information you provide and how it is used. we will explain what we intend to do with it. We will also refer to the relevant Privacy notices for further information.
  * If you've already agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you can change your mind by contacting us directly, altering your preferences or by selecting the 'unsubscribe' link at the bottom of any marketing emails we send you.
  * If you think any of the information we hold about you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us and we will correct any information that is incorrect or incomplete.

## Is my information secure?

We are committed to keeping your information secure, and we have physical, electronic and managerial procedures in place to safeguard the information we collect from you.

You should be aware of the following rules, however:

  * When you email us, the possibility exists, however remote, that unauthorised people might be able to intercept your message. You should never use unsecure forms and email to send personal data such as financial information to us. If you are considering returning your form by email then please visit our [returning forms ](http://www.bournemouth.ac.uk/return-forms) webpage to find out more about how to encrypt your form before emailing it.
  * When we transfer and receive personal data, we direct you to a web connection that uses encryption (similar to that used for online banking). If you are in a secure part of our website, you'll see a padlock symbol in your address or status bar.
  * Some of our forms allow you to ask questions about our products or services. These messages are not sent over an encrypted connection and the possibility exists, however remote, that unauthorised people may be able to intercept this information.
  * We aren't responsible for the privacy of emails except those stored on our own servers.

There are steps you can take to protect your personal information while using our website and applications:

  * Never leave your computer while you're logged into any of our applications
  * Be aware that public Wi-Fi (wireless) internet connections and internet cafes could leave your data at risk
  * You should decline any username or password recognition options presented to you
  * You should always log out of any BU applications when you have finished and close the internet browser after logging out. Simply disconnecting from the internet is no enough
  * Never share your username and password with anyone or leave these details somewhere where others may be able to access them.

## What about links to other websites?

Our website contains links to other websites. We don't have any control over the websites we link to, so we can't be held responsible for the protection and privacy of any information you provide on those websites. The websites we link to aren't governed by this privacy statement and you should look at their privacy statements to make sure you are happy with how they will handle your data before you submit any personal information. See our [website terms and conditions](https://www1.bournemouth.ac.uk/about/governance/website-terms-and-conditions) for more information.
